DAVID CARDENAS

Technician

Arvada, CO 80003

davidcardenas1993@yahoo.com

720-347-0250

My name is David Cardenas, and I am a fleet technician for the City and County of Denver's Police Fleet. I currently hold about 3 and a half years of experience of automotive and heavy equipment diagnosis and repair work. I have performed work ranging from complete engine/tranny removal and reinstall to preventative maintenance (tires, oil changes, filters). I am always willing to learn and be educated on something new or even a refresh on something that I already know. I am also, currently learning to code/program at the University of Denver.



------ WORK EXPERIENCE

Fleet Technician 1

City and County of Denver Police - Denver, CO

November 2018 to Present

Perform routine maintenance on all police fleet vehicles. Perform minor diagnostics. Communicate effectively with officers and supervisor of the concerns found with vehicles. Perform all repairs.

Fleet Technician 2

City and County of Denver - Denver, CO

August 2017 to November 2018

Perform major maintenance services and repairs on city equipment ranging from semi/tractor trailer, trash truck, dump truck, CAT products, street sweepers, traffic equipment, and more.

Service Technician

Echo Park Automotive - Thornton, CO

July 2017 to August 2017

Perform full vehicle inspections on used vehicles. Repair any defects found on vehicle from tires to manifold gaskets to head gaskets.

Technician

Larry H Miller Volkswagen - Lakewood, CO

July 2015 to July 2017

I have progressed here from a lube technician, to an apprentice technician, to a full technician. I am responsible for verifying customer concerns and fixing customer concerns with their vehicles ranging from preventative maintenance to transmission r and r to engine r and r.

Lube Technician

Lakewood Empire Nissan - Lakewood, CO

December 2014 to July 2015

Responsibilities

Oil changes, tire rotations, tire patching/mounting/balancing, inspections of vehicles, maintain clean work bay.

Accomplishments

I worked as a team to complete light maintenance in a timely manner for vehicles.

Skills Used

Attention to detail, repetition, lifting and bending, proficiency with computers, communication.

General Service Technician

Firestone Complete Auto Care - Lakewood, CO

October 2014 to November 2014

United States)

Oil changes, Tire changes/rotations, Tire flat repairs, Organize and stock the store room.

Food Service Assistant

Wide Horizon - Wheat Ridge, CO October 2012 to October 2014

United States)

Clean up kitchen. I wipe down all the counters, shelves, and sinks. I sweep and mop the floors. I sweep and mop major messes that occur in the resident's dining area. I work as a team to prepare meals for the resident's.



EDUCATION

Programming/coding certificate in Information Technology

University of Denver - Denver, CO June 2019 to December 2019

Diploma in General

Denver Online High School - Denver, CO 2014

Associates of applied science in Automotive

Front Range Community College - Westminster, CO



SKILLS

Caterpillar, Heavy Equipment, Volkswagen, Microsoft Office (4 years), Bootstrap (Less than 1 year), Gitbash (Less than 1 year), Visual Studio Code (Less than 1 year), Github (Less than 1 year), Gitlab (Less than 1 year), JQuery (Less than 1 year), Javascript (Less than 1 year), Node.js (Less than 1 year), Axios (Less than 1 year), JSON (Less than 1 year), SQL (Less than 1 year), Express (Less than 1 year)



AWARDS

Volkswagen fast track completion

June 2017

Completed program for technician training in fast track program.



CERTIFICATIONS AND LICENSES

Fork lift certified

CDL Class A

December 2017 to September 2021

section 609 a/c recovery

February 2018 to Present

Driver's License

Hybrid Vehicle training

Present

I have completed automotive training on hybrid vehicle systems from the Automotive Training Authority.

Diesel Vehicle Emissions Systems

Present

I have completed Diesel Emissions training on diesel vehicles up to 2019.



ASSESSMENTS

English Communication Skills: Typing — Expert

May 2019

Transcribing text using a standard keyboard.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/share_assignment/ibdapzlotgxlcx-o

Basic Computer Skills: PC — Proficient

June 2019

Performing basic computer operations, navigating a Windows OS, and troubleshooting common computer problems.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/share_assignment/l5pirp1dzceb77vf

| any professional field. |
|-------------------------|
| |
| |
| |
| |
| |
| |
| |
| |
| |
| |
| |
| |
| |
| |
| |
| |
| |
| |
| |
| |
| |